A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Subject Files FA835
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Subject Files
1915-1955 (includes 1907-1914 Clyde, NJ)
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA835
4 box(es)
4 boxes.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 425-3
Arrangement
Arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
Scope and Contents
Subject arrangement of correspondence, contracts, blueprints and reports dealing with Princeton properties.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Other Finding Aids
FA834 Rockefeller University records, Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Princeton, NJ, Correspondence.
FA968 Rockefeller University records, Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Princeton, NJ, Carl TenBroeck papers.
FA969 Rockefeller University records, Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Princeton, NJ, Publications.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for scholarly research.
Due to the oversize nature and potentially brittle condition of some of this material, special arrangements may be required in order to view materials. Individual items may be restricted due to preservation concerns.
Diseases; Plant diseases; Medical research; Medicine, Preventive; Biochemistry; Animals -- Diseases; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Medical sciences; Technology; Medical technology; Pathology; Biology -- Research; Life sciences; Medical education; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Banks in Princeton, 1916-1946 (Box 1)
- Buildings (dwellings), 1910-1950 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  See also Construction.
- Cattle 1946 with NY State Veterinary College (Cornell) (Box 1)
- Clyde, NJ, 1907-1934 (Box 1)
  Includes reports Jan. 30, 1912 and Jan. 1914. Purchase, sale and difficulties with personnel and mortgage.
- Coal hauling (Walter Sachs), 1941-1949 (Box 1)
- Construction (other than dwellings), 1915-1931 (Box 1)
  Includes agreements and specifications.
- Construction (other than dwellings), 1932-1947 (Box 1)
- Deeds, agreements, title abstract, 1915-1950 (Box 1)
- Deeds (correspondence and blueprints) (Box 2)
- Delaware and Raritan Canal, 1915-1945 (Box 2)
  (includes Mosquito control).
- Development Committee, 1913-1921 (Box 2)
  Includes 1913 report on visits to European Institutes; includes planting design by Beatrix Farrand, 1916; 1921.
- Electrical construction, 1917-1938 (Box 2)
  (including Power House and Public Service Elec. Co.).
- Employees, 1916-1949 (Box 2)
  (Primarily special arrangements for long-term illness).
- Employees (Box 2)
  (Correspondence by and about Reed, Ring, Roeder, Shaw).
- Farm, 1916-1952 (Box 2)
  (Includes correspondence with Commodity Credit Corp. and Farmers' Coop. Assoc.) also correspondence with Voorhees Hunt.
- Forestry, 1917-1951
  (includes lumber contract 1950).
- Insurance, 1930-1951 (Box 2)
- Mosquito control (Box 3)
  (see Delaware and Raritan Canal).
- New Jersey (State), 1914-1942 (Box 3)
  Includes Agricultural Experiment Station and Highway Commission regarding Trenton/Hew Brunswick Turnpike.
- Property acquisition, 1914-1951 (Box 3)
  (Purchases and leases including summary made at time of sale).
- Receptions or meetings, 1932-1946 (Box 3)
- Sale of property, 1947-1951; 2 folders (Box 3)
  (Includes library inventory).
- Storeroom (Box 3)
- Surveyor, 1914-1931 (Box 3)
  (includes work on roads).
- Telephone, 1915-1918 (Box 3)
- Theobald Smith House, 1931-1936 (Box 3)
  (Includes remodeling and refurnishing).
- Sewage disposal and water, 1915-1916 June (Box 4)
- Sewage disposal and water, 1916 July-1942 (Box 4)
- Sunday work, 1917-1918 (Box 4)
- Taxes, 1916-1951 (Box 4)
- Underpass, 1932 (Box 4)
- Walker-Gordon, 1913-1950 (Box 4)
  Original negotiations relating to right-of-way through property, also correspondence relating to leases and land exchanges; excerpts from Minutes 1915-1929 dealing with cooperative experimental arrangements.
- Wartime rationing (Box 4)
  (includes car needs).
- Wicoff, 1915-1951 (Box 4)
  Correspondence regarding legal service rendered. Includes purchases of Williamson, Robison and Jemison property.